<Gff Version="1" Type="UTI">
    <DWord Name="AddCost">0</DWord>
    <Int Name="BaseItem">74</Int>
    <Byte Name="Charges">0</Byte>
    <CExoString Name="Comment"></CExoString>
    <DWord Name="Cost">1001</DWord>
    <CExoLocString Name="DescIdentified">
        <DWord Name="StringRef">4294967295</DWord>
        <SubString>
            <Int Name="StringID">0</Int>
            <CExoString Name="String">Welcome to Anphillia!  

Please read this document as it contains useful information for your journeys here.

Anphillia is a land at war.  The 2 sides, Axfell and Cleaven, have been at war for generations.  You have probably already picked a side :).

The premise is that you likely grew up in the town you picked, so everyone there is part of your community, treat them as such.  All players on a given side should band together and form a tight knit group, helping each other as much as possible.

If you want to come from another land, that is fine too, but at present you must pick a side.

THIS IS A ROLEPLAY SERVER!  Please try to stay in character.  The environment setup should make it easy.

You are at war!  There will be PvP against the other side.  However, I would ask that you not attack people who are weaker than yourself, and if they flee, let them run.  However, if both parties wish to fight, then that is fine.

There are now perimeter guards setup that should be very difficult to pass through for the opposing team.  This will give lower level characters lots of room to grow without worrying about being attacked.

We have many DM's who will come on and reward experience for roleplaying.  I'm sorry it is difficult to watch every conversation, but we will try.  We will also setup quests for people to do etc.

This server uses the HCR ruleset, with a number of modifications. Here are some things you should be aware of:

Death:

When your HP go down to 0, you are knocked unconcious.  At this point you lie there waiting for someone to help you.  A medicine bag or healing potion may be used on an unconscious person to stabalize or revive them.  There is a chance when in this state, you will come to on your own, but it's best to have a friend to help you!

Death is not permanent.  Instead, you are sent to fugue, where you can use exit at any time, taking an experience penalty of lvl * lvl * 20 + 200.  You will also drop your gold, to a maximum of 10000gp.  When you die, a corpse is left behind.  This corpse may then be picked up and brought to an NPC cleric to be raised.  Both sides have clerics in their barracks.  These clerics charge a minimal fee of 100gp/lvl + 100gp.  You may also cast raise dead etc. on the corpses. The corpses may also be "used" on a campfire.  This makes them burn, so that they cannot be raised (do this to members of the opposite team obviously).   If raised via a cleric, or with a raise dead spell, you suffer no penalties (except the gold loss).

If you die, and the server crashes, you will rejoin in fugue, and your corpse will be left near the monument in town.

Resting:
When resting, you gain back 1hp/lvl.  Resting is limited to every 8 hours with a bedroll, and every 24 without.  You may also rest in the barracks at any time to regain full health (the cleric there heals you as you rest).

Misc:
Oil flasks can be used to make campfires.  You can sit around these, or cook meat on them, or use them to burn corpses. 
Copper skinning knives available at the general store to skin animals you kill.
Medicine bags can be used to stabalize a dying friend, and to heal potion or disease.
The potions are the HCR variety.  They are available in the 'misc' section at stores, and can be used on others.
The ball of saving in your inventory may be used to save your character at any time.  Use this when you find treasure etc. so that you do not lose it due to a crash.

Experience:

The experience system has been rewritten.  The experience handed out is the same regardless of whether you are in a party or not.  You do not get experience when killing monsters greater than 6 levels above you (or below).
This server is generally considered quite difficult.  You will likely to have to join with other players in order to make headway.  Soloing can be done, but it would be very difficult.

If you have any suggestions, feel free to visit us in IRC
irc.esper.net:6667 - Channel #anphillia
or visit the forums in http://www.anphillia.com/phpBB2

Enjoy!</CExoString>
        </SubString>
    </CExoLocString>
    <CExoLocString Name="Description">
        <DWord Name="StringRef">4294967295</DWord>
        <SubString>
            <Int Name="StringID">0</Int>
            <CExoString Name="String"></CExoString>
        </SubString>
    </CExoLocString>
    <Byte Name="Identified">1</Byte>
    <CExoLocString Name="LocalizedName">
        <DWord Name="StringRef">4294967295</DWord>
        <SubString>
            <Int Name="StringID">0</Int>
            <CExoString Name="String">Anphillia Information</CExoString>
        </SubString>
    </CExoLocString>
    <Byte Name="ModelPart1">7</Byte>
    <Byte Name="PaletteID">60</Byte>
    <Byte Name="Plot">1</Byte>
    <List Name="PropertiesList">
        <Struct Id="0">
            <Byte Name="ChanceAppear">100</Byte>
            <Byte Name="CostTable">10</Byte>
            <Word Name="CostValue">5</Word>
            <Byte Name="Param1">255</Byte>
            <Byte Name="Param1Value">0</Byte>
            <Word Name="PropertyName">11</Word>
            <Word Name="Subtype">0</Word>
        </Struct>
    </List>
    <Word Name="StackSize">1</Word>
    <Byte Name="Stolen">0</Byte>
    <CExoString Name="Tag">AnphilliaInformation</CExoString>
    <ResRef Name="TemplateResRef">anphilliainforma</ResRef>
</Gff>
