<Gff Version="1" Type="UTI">
    <DWord Name="AddCost">6</DWord>
    <Int Name="BaseItem">74</Int>
    <Byte Name="Charges">0</Byte>
    <CExoString Name="Comment"></CExoString>
    <DWord Name="Cost">1007</DWord>
    <CExoLocString Name="DescIdentified">
        <DWord Name="StringRef">4294967295</DWord>
        <SubString>
            <Int Name="StringID">0</Int>
            <CExoString Name="String">Our story begins with a woman named Shilar.  Shilar was a devout cleric, and would spend many of her days in solitude worshiping.  She was often sickened by the state of the people around her, and while offering to help was also greatly saddened by their lack of spirituality.  Eventually she decided that she would seek refuge in a new place.  So she and some of her closest followers left on a voyage across the ocean in search of new lands and solitude.

After many moons on the ocean, they came to an island.  They landed on the southern edge of this island and proceeded to explore.  The going was difficult, with thick brush covering many parts, and untamed monsters roaming free.  However, even in their short trip they found many interesting artifacts and mineral deposits.

Deciding this was just what she was looking for, Shilar erected a small sanctuary on a smaller island just off the southern coast.  Many of her followers though, did not wish to stay in seclusion any longer so they agreed to allow those who wished, to return on the boat to the mainland.

They sailed safely back and were quite happy to return to civilization.  Their tales of the mysterious island were told to others and eventually the king of the lands heard of the news.

After speaking with one of the returned followers, the King decided to send a large party to the island in search of treasures and ore.

A detachment of his army was sent, along with many prisoners to be used as miners.  The captain of this army was Gord MacCleaven, a noble warrior whose father had also served the King, and in whom the king had great trust.  MacCleaven was a good man - wise, strong, and dutiful.  To make the most of the trip, a renowned Dwarven miner by the name of Gredius Thundarmane was brought along to guide the workers.

They sailed the long voyage to what the King dubbed 'Anphillia'.  Their orders were to setup a port there, and begin harvesting the treasures of the land.  The King would send boats periodically to bring the gathered treasure back to the mainland.

Once there they began work immediately.  The Dwarf Gredius was in charge of mining operations, while the noble MacCleaven and his army was to rid the island of monsters, and search for above-land treasures.  The first order of business however, was the construction of a port on the southern end of the island.  This was named 'Ranzington' and became the main station for the militia and workers.

Shilar was dismayed that her island was now the home of military men and prisoners, but they generally left Shilar to her small island off Anphillia so she did not mind too much.

One evening when Shilar was preparing for sleep, her God came to her and told her of the great wars that would one day come to the land.  She was asked by her God to try to ease the suffering of the war torn peoples, but that she must choose her actions wisely, as anything act of helping one side may be viewed by the other as hostile.  She was also told of a great artifact laying hidden on the island that held great power and must never be discovered.

Shilar spoke to only a few of her followers about this meeting with her God.  However, it was not long before all Shilars followers knew the story, and not long after that before the whole island had heard it.  Many did not believe them of course, but many did.

Shipments of ore, gold and artifacts were sent back to the mainland, much to the glee of the King.  The rumors of course, were also shipped back.  The whole thing was kept a great secret, as the King did not wish to have to compete for the island.  However, in order to deduce the nature of some artifacts, one of the Kings servants unknowingly called upon the help of a Drow who would disguise himself in order to trade in the city.  This Drow learned of the rumors and general location of the island and returned with the news to his family.

The Drow had their own ancient knowledge of such a place, but this piqued their interest.  Eventually 2 Drow houses, Tarik and Kazar, left for the island to find the artifact to gain favor with Lloth.  The voyage would take many years, traveling through the underdark in an attempt to locate it.

After some months on the island, Gredius' greedy nature got the best of him.  He had grown attached to many of the prisoners, many of whom he felt a kinship for as they were Dwarven like himself.  He also couldn't bare to see the great riches of the island sent back to the mainland with him and his workers receiving nothing.  So, with promises of great riches and freedom for all, he convinced the prisoners to rise against MacCleavens army and take the island for themselves.

While mining, some within the mine would instead craft, creating weapons and armor for the battle ahead.  They would hide them in the deepest recesses of the caves at night for fear MacCleavens militia might find them.

Eventually they had enough.  Gredius staged an early morning raid on Ranzington in an attempt to block further ships from returning to the island, and to rid the island of the men loyal to the king and to MacCleaven.  MacCleavens army however was forever prepared for such raids, having been ready for attacks by any number of monsters on the island.  The Rauts had been especially difficult.  MacCleavens army was unable to hold the port, but suffered minimal casualties in their retreat.  Under Gredius' rule, the now freed prisoners, established a fort and mining base in the eastern portion of the island.  This they dubbed 'Axfell' as a symbol of their ongoing fight for freedom.

MacCleavens army established a fort northwest of their original location.

It was not long before the Axfell attacked again, this time destroying the fort built by MacCleaven and his army.  MacCleaven himself was also slain in this battle.  Upon MacCleavens death, the troops fled still further to the west where they established a much larger, stronger fort. This was named 'Fort Cleaven' after their fallen captain.  Here they successfully held off several more attacks by the Axfell over the years.

Soon after the establishment of the Cleaven fort, the Drow arrive.  The Kazar set about locating ancient treasures on the island.  They found several locations which seemed to have strong magic, and created golems to excavate these sites.  Meanwhile, the Tarik sent out scouting parties at night to determine the surfacers strength and locations.

Soon they struck - in the dark of night they attacked the Axfell.  Both houses layed siege to the town.  Little did the Kazar know however, that the Tarik had been plotting against them.  The Tarik wanted the treasures and the artifact for themselves, so they turned on the Kazar in the heat of battle, slaying most of the Kazar house members.

However, the Tarik had underestimated the strength of the Axfell, and lost many numbers themselves, forcing them to retreat.  A number of Kazar were left on the surface with no where to go.  If they returned to the underdark then would be slain by the Tarik.  Many became renegades, while some were captured by the Axfell and became slaves or eventually joined their ranks.

The Tarik house continued to live in the underdark and control the dig sites.  The Golems were created in a hurry, and were programmed to simply dig up artifacts and place them in a chest.  All that was required is that they allow the golems to continue digging and check the chests periodically.  Raids are still staged against the surfacers in hopes of uncovering the artifact, to collect slaves and to win the favor of the evil Lloth.

Shilar and her followers continued to help those on the island, aiding travellers of both sides alike, until one day she was found herself in terrible situation.  She was tending to a group of wounded Cleaven militia who had just been jumped by a powerful group of Axfell.  It seemed however that the Axfell had followed them, as soon after Shilar had started her prayers they were once again upon them.  So swift were the Axfell in their attack they failed to even recognize Shilar and she was killed in one mighty blow.

It was a sad day for Shilars followers, but they understood the dangers of their position and vowed to continue in Shilars tradition, being ever so careful not to be seen as taking sides.

Boats from the mainland continued to come to the razed port town of Ranzington.  These new arrivals took on the chore of rebuilding the town.  It was built much more defensively than the original in hopes that it would not fall again. 

These people were not warriors nor terribly loyal to the king.  They were mostly merchants being paid for their transportation services, along with some curious passengers who wished to go to the island for various reasons.

Once Ranzington was reconstructed, some wearily decided to stay and trade with those on the island, knowing very well that the inhabitants were not to be trusted.  Many others returned to the mainland to bring the news of Anphillias state to the king.  Upon their return however, they found a land decimated by a great plague.  The plague killed so many on the mainland that society there was cast into chaos.  Many who arrived attempted to return to Anphillia, but they were already infected, and died en-route.

And so all ties to the kingdom on the mainland were lost, and the battles continue to rage on Anphillia.

(Story by Vico)
</CExoString>
        </SubString>
    </CExoLocString>
    <CExoLocString Name="Description">
        <DWord Name="StringRef">13002</DWord>
        <SubString>
            <Int Name="StringID">0</Int>
            <CExoString Name="String">Our story begins with a woman named Shilar.  Shilar was a devout cleric, and would spend many of her days in solitude worshiping.  She was often sickened by the state of the people around her, and while offering to help was also greatly saddened by their lack of spirituality.  Eventually she decided that she would seek refuge in a new place.  So she and some of her closest followers left on a voyage across the ocean in search of new lands and solitude.

After many moons on the ocean, they came to an island.  They landed on the southern edge of this island and proceeded to explore.  The going was difficult, with thick brush covering many parts, and untamed monsters roaming free.  However, even in their short trip they found many interesting artifacts and mineral deposits.

Deciding this was just what she was looking for, Shilar erected a small sanctuary on a smaller island just off the southern coast.  Many of her followers though, did not wish to stay in seclusion any longer so they agreed to allow those who wished, to return on the boat to the mainland.

They sailed safely back and were quite happy to return to civilization.  Their tales of the mysterious island were told to others and eventually the king of the lands heard of the news.

After speaking with one of the returned followers, the King decided to send a large party to the island in search of treasures and ore.

A detachment of his army was sent, along with many prisoners to be used as miners.  The captain of this army was Gord MacCleaven, a noble warrior whose father had also served the King, and in whom the king had great trust.  MacCleaven was a good man - wise, strong, and dutiful.  To make the most of the trip, a renowned Dwarven miner by the name of Gredius Thundarmane was brought along to guide the workers.

They sailed the long voyage to what the King dubbed 'Anphillia'.  Their orders were to setup a port there, and begin harvesting the treasures of the land.  The King would send boats periodically to bring the gathered treasure back to the mainland.

Once there they began work immediately.  The Dwarf Gredius was in charge of mining operations, while the noble MacCleaven and his army was to rid the island of monsters, and search for above-land treasures.  The first order of business however, was the construction of a port on the southern end of the island.  This was named 'Ranzington' and became the main station for the militia and workers.

Shilar was dismayed that her island was now the home of military men and prisoners, but they generally left Shilar to her small island off Anphillia so she did not mind too much.

One evening when Shilar was preparing for sleep, her God came to her and told her of the great wars that would one day come to the land.  She was asked by her God to try to ease the suffering of the war torn peoples, but that she must choose her actions wisely, as anything act of helping one side may be viewed by the other as hostile.  She was also told of a great artifact laying hidden on the island that held great power and must never be discovered.

Shilar spoke to only a few of her followers about this meeting with her God.  However, it was not long before all Shilars followers knew the story, and not long after that before the whole island had heard it.  Many did not believe them of course, but many did.

Shipments of ore, gold and artifacts were sent back to the mainland, much to the glee of the King.  The rumors of course, were also shipped back.  The whole thing was kept a great secret, as the King did not wish to have to compete for the island.  However, in order to deduce the nature of some artifacts, one of the Kings servants unknowingly called upon the help of a Drow who would disguise himself in order to trade in the city.  This Drow learned of the rumors and general location of the island and returned with the news to his family.

The Drow had their own ancient knowledge of such a place, but this piqued their interest.  Eventually 2 Drow houses, Tarik and Kazar, left for the island to find the artifact to gain favor with Lloth.  The voyage would take many years, traveling through the underdark in an attempt to locate it.

After some months on the island, Gredius' greedy nature got the best of him.  He had grown attached to many of the prisoners, many of whom he felt a kinship for as they were Dwarven like himself.  He also couldn't bare to see the great riches of the island sent back to the mainland with him and his workers receiving nothing.  So, with promises of great riches and freedom for all, he convinced the prisoners to rise against MacCleavens army and take the island for themselves.

While mining, some within the mine would instead craft, creating weapons and armor for the battle ahead.  They would hide them in the deepest recesses of the caves at night for fear MacCleavens militia might find them.

Eventually they had enough.  Gredius staged an early morning raid on Ranzington in an attempt to block further ships from returning to the island, and to rid the island of the men loyal to the king and to MacCleaven.  MacCleavens army however was forever prepared for such raids, having been ready for attacks by any number of monsters on the island.  The Rauts had been especially difficult.  MacCleavens army was unable to hold the port, but suffered minimal casualties in their retreat.  Under Gredius' rule, the now freed prisoners, established a fort and mining base in the eastern portion of the island.  This they dubbed 'Axfell' as a symbol of their ongoing fight for freedom.

MacCleavens army established a fort northwest of their original location.

It was not long before the Axfell attacked again, this time destroying the fort built by MacCleaven and his army.  MacCleaven himself was also slain in this battle.  Upon MacCleavens death, the troops fled still further to the west where they established a much larger, stronger fort. This was named 'Fort Cleaven' after their fallen captain.  Here they successfully held off several more attacks by the Axfell over the years.

Soon after the establishment of the Cleaven fort, the Drow arrive.  The Kazar set about locating ancient treasures on the island.  They found several locations which seemed to have strong magic, and created golems to excavate these sites.  Meanwhile, the Tarik sent out scouting parties at night to determine the surfacers strength and locations.

Soon they struck - in the dark of night they attacked the Axfell.  Both houses layed siege to the town.  Little did the Kazar know however, that the Tarik had been plotting against them.  The Tarik wanted the treasures and the artifact for themselves, so they turned on the Kazar in the heat of battle, slaying most of the Kazar house members.

However, the Tarik had underestimated the strength of the Axfell, and lost many numbers themselves, forcing them to retreat.  A number of Kazar were left on the surface with no where to go.  If they returned to the underdark then would be slain by the Tarik.  Many became renegades, while some were captured by the Axfell and became slaves or eventually joined their ranks.

The Tarik house continued to live in the underdark and control the dig sites.  The Golems were created in a hurry, and were programmed to simply dig up artifacts and place them in a chest.  All that was required is that they allow the golems to continue digging and check the chests periodically.  Raids are still staged against the surfacers in hopes of uncovering the artifact, to collect slaves and to win the favor of the evil Lloth.

Shilar and her followers continued to help those on the island, aiding travellers of both sides alike, until one day she was found herself in terrible situation.  She was tending to a group of wounded Cleaven militia who had just been jumped by a powerful group of Axfell.  It seemed however that the Axfell had followed them, as soon after Shilar had started her prayers they were once again upon them.  So swift were the Axfell in their attack they failed to even recognize Shilar and she was killed in one mighty blow.

It was a sad day for Shilars followers, but they understood the dangers of their position and vowed to continue in Shilars tradition, being ever so careful not to be seen as taking sides.

Boats from the mainland continued to come to the razed port town of Ranzington.  These new arrivals took on the chore of rebuilding the town.  It was built much more defensively than the original in hopes that it would not fall again. 

These people were not warriors nor terribly loyal to the king.  They were mostly merchants being paid for their transportation services, along with some curious passengers who wished to go to the island for various reasons.

Once Ranzington was reconstructed, some wearily decided to stay and trade with those on the island, knowing very well that the inhabitants were not to be trusted.  Many others returned to the mainland to bring the news of Anphillias state to the king.  Upon their return however, they found a land decimated by a great plague.  The plague killed so many on the mainland that society there was cast into chaos.  Many who arrived attempted to return to Anphillia, but they were already infected, and died en-route.

And so all ties to the kingdom on the mainland were lost, and the battles continue to rage on Anphillia.

(Story by Vico)
</CExoString>
        </SubString>
    </CExoLocString>
    <Byte Name="Identified">1</Byte>
    <CExoLocString Name="LocalizedName">
        <DWord Name="StringRef">13001</DWord>
        <SubString>
            <Int Name="StringID">0</Int>
            <CExoString Name="String">History of Anphillia</CExoString>
        </SubString>
    </CExoLocString>
    <Byte Name="ModelPart1">5</Byte>
    <Byte Name="PaletteID">54</Byte>
    <Byte Name="Plot">1</Byte>
    <List Name="PropertiesList">
        <Struct Id="0">
            <Byte Name="ChanceAppear">100</Byte>
            <Byte Name="CostTable">10</Byte>
            <Word Name="CostValue">5</Word>
            <Byte Name="Param1">255</Byte>
            <Byte Name="Param1Value">0</Byte>
            <Word Name="PropertyName">11</Word>
            <Word Name="Subtype">0</Word>
        </Struct>
    </List>
    <Word Name="StackSize">1</Word>
    <Byte Name="Stolen">0</Byte>
    <CExoString Name="Tag">Anphillia_History</CExoString>
    <ResRef Name="TemplateResRef">anphillia_histor</ResRef>
</Gff>
