<Gff Version="1" Type="UTI">
    <DWord Name="AddCost">0</DWord>
    <Int Name="BaseItem">74</Int>
    <Byte Name="Charges">0</Byte>
    <CExoString Name="Comment"></CExoString>
    <DWord Name="Cost">1001</DWord>
    <CExoLocString Name="DescIdentified">
        <DWord Name="StringRef">4294967295</DWord>
        <SubString>
            <Int Name="StringID">0</Int>
            <CExoString Name="String">Please read these rules. Not knowing these rules will not prevent punishment. The most recent rules may be found from http://www.anphillia.com/phpBB2

--- General ---

.) Have fun! That's what you are here for and that's what we are trying to provide.
.) Please try not to have fun at the cost of others, they are here to have fun too.
.) Do not try to drop undroppable items. Undroppables include your army ring, horn and key, this rulebook, the emote wand and some other items. If you are unable to drop a certain item, it is an undroppable. Don't try more than once. Attempted drops are logged in the server log and broadcasted to all DMs.
.) If you find an exploit or bug, do not abuse it. Report it to a DM as soon as possible. Exploiting bugs can bring harsh punishments upon you (and - depending of the nature of this exploit/bug - may lead to something worse).

--- Roleplay ---

.) Stay in character (IC)! This server is focused on roleplay. We will try to reward playing in character as best we can.
.) Try to "live" your character. Try to play the choices you made at character creation (low intelligence, low charisma). It can be hard to play a "dumb" character sometimes, but it can be very rewarding!
.) A player must ask permission to transfer factions (Axfell/Cleaven) to (Cleaven/Axfell) BEFORE roleplaying it (A DM or possessed NPC will be the only one who gives permission).


--- Character Appearance/Naming ---

.) Head models that have horns (head "gear" counts too) are not allowed.
.) Using names of commonly known from fantasy stories/cartoons/series/worlds/games is not allowed.
.) No descriptive names like "Jared the Wild" or "Jason 'Eagle-Eye' Draian".
.) No colors in names.
.) No special Characters (_, &amp;, - etc...) in Names, only Characters and Spaces.
.) Your name should be a name everyone could imagine actually given to you at birth. I don't see many "Erik the Wild" or "Grimbag Strongfist" babies, do you? This includes female names to males and vice versa.

--- NPCs ---

.) Do not do anything considered hostile against the NPCs in your town. They are part of your army and supposed to be your comrades/superiors. Attacking them intentionally is way out of character (OOC).
.) The NWN AI considers many things as "hostile action", this includes certain spells like Darkness too: So it is better not to cast spells around NPCs.
.) If you would like to "practice" spells/counterspells and melee please do this away from any NPC's

---Chat ---

.) Shouting without DM consent is strictly forbidden as it harms the roleplay environment. Please ask a DM before doing a shout (which then HAS to be IC).
.) No profanity, dirty language is allowed in any channel. This is to protect minors and for atmosphere purposes.
.) Stay IC all the time while using the Talk Channel.
.) OOC Talk is only allowed using Tells.
.) Things like "afk" and "brb" are NOT wanted here. Try to make up IC statements. Everyone has to go to the toiled or eat or drink for time to time. Guess what, your character needs to do these things too. Try to "convert" these OOC statements into IC talk.
.) If there is no way around an OOC message in talk, please mark it as OOC by putting "OOC: " or "//" or "((" before the actual text.
.) If you will ever be caught talking about stats/experience/levels/numbers, wheter marked OOC or not, you will be punished for sure.
.) Try to reduce abbrievations or "chatroom talk", for example "ss - stoneskin", or "bs - bullstrength" What you say on the talk channel is considered what is coming out of your mouth.

--- Logging ---

.) Logging off and on constantly is not allowed. All characters are saved regularly. Logging off and on will be interpreted as an exploit to restore spells upon reentering.
.) Logging to avoid death is not allowed and should you be caught, the punishment will by far exceed the penalty death would have caused you.
.) Logging to avoid PvP (Player vs. Player) Death is not allowed. Punishment for doing so is even worse than the penalty for being caught logging to avoid PvM (Player vs. Monster) Death.

--- Movement ---

.) Walking is encouraged at all time (except in a fight). People don't run around all the time, they walk.
.) Walking around heavily encumbard is not realistic...unless it is a death march (carring corpse back to fort for resurrection. If we see players continually doing this expect to have monsters attack you while you are slow).
.) Sidestepping to avoid slow while encumbard is also exploiting a bug...expect to be punished if caught.

---Powergaming ---

.) Powergaming is not allowed. If you solely play to gain XP and "show off", you have chosen the wrong server...
.) If you are disturbed by a powergamer please take screen shots for proof and send via private message to one of the DM's. We will try to keep an eye on such players.

---Parties ---

.) We ask you not to create parties (in a game mechanic sense) as they cause lag. Once Bioware fixed that problem or we found a workaround, we will get rid of this rule again. But until then, stay out of parties so there is no lag.
.) Solo-ing (runnind around with less than 3 people) is not allowed. You are part of an army and your superiors ordered you not to run around alone.
.) On some occasions and for some classes, solo-ing is allowed. Good Examples are a scouting rogue, a ranger/druid seeking refuge and wanting to be alone, or if you are around for RP-ing purposes. Solo-ing to kill creatures/gain XP/get crafting resources IS forbidden.
.) Solo-ers (or groups with less than 3 people) could and will run into unbeatable encounters to show them how dangerous solo-ing is. You have been warned.
.) Even scouts and other chracters that are "allowed to solo" need to ask the permission from DMs before soloing.

--- Death/Dying ---

.) This server uses a modified dying system. When you die and "respawn" you are sent to fugue. There are three ways out of fugue. You lose a level-based amount of XP when dying (getting to -10).
.) When raised, you appear where you died.
.) When talking to the Glowing Sphere in Fugue, you are sent back to your starting location, with your backpack remaining where it was. You will lose XP again when respawning this way.
.) There are so-called "Safe-Levels". These are level 5, 10 and 15. Once achieving these levels, you should be in "relative safety". There is a chance you might drop below a safe-level when dying though.
.) Level-loss below Level 5 is 50*Level, from 6-14 it's Lvl*Lvl*20+200, and above 15 it's whatever you are above 15 divided by 2.
.) There are no safe-levels in regards to burning.
.) Grabbing a corpse to raise it in faction jail is not allowed without the permission of the subject

--- Burning/Player Corpses ---

.) Picking up bodies during a fight is not allowed. After the fight has ended, you are allowed to pick up the enemy body to burn it.
.) Bodynapping (taking a body with you without the intention to burn/scalp) is not allowed. If you don't burn/scalp them, leave them there so his/her friends can come to rescue him. Setting up an ambush that way is allowed!
.) If you burn a character, you must have an IC reason for doing so. Most characters will probably consider such an act as barbaric and will not only refrain from doing it themselves but even try to prevent burnings.
.) When burned by a member of the enemy faction, the XP penalty for respawning will be 1/4. You will be sent back to your starting location.
.) When burned by a member of your own faction, you will be sent to your starting location and lose full XP.
.) If burning a faction member, you will lose the same amount of XP like the Person you burned.
.) Raising an enemy just to kill him again is not allowed.

--- Tradeskills (CnR) ---

.) We are using CnR (Craftable natural Resources) on Anphillia. You cannot master all tradeskills on your own, because we set a level-Cap (55 when i wrote this).
.) Teamwork will lead to success.

--- Deities ---

.) Choosing a deity is encouraged for every character.
.) Every clerical character NEEDS to have a deity. It is advised that you choose your clerical domains according to your deity.
.) Paladins count as clerical characters.
.) Druids and Rangers aren't forced to choose a deity, but are encouraged to do so.
.) As a cleric you MUST roleplay prayer to your Gods as well as following their specific doctorin or domain. We understand it is hard to do it during battle but something short after battle (Thank you God for sparing me/granting me the gift of ressurecting my fallen comrades) will do. If you do not regularily worship your God you will lose your gifts....

--- Multi-Classing ---

.) A character changing his class has to be at least level 11 in his primary class.
.) The change in Class MUST have IC reasons and the classes have to fit together.
.) A multiclassed character can reach max. lvl 15 in his primary class.
.) Here are the multi-class restrictions:

Barbarian: may not become Monk, Paladin, Wizard, Sorcerer, Rogue, Bard or Cleric.
Bard: may not become Monk, Paladin, Ranger, Barbarian or Sorcerer.
Cleric: may not become Monk, Paladin, Ranger or Sorcerer.
Druid: may not become Monk, Paladin, Bard, Rogue, Wizard or Sorcerer.
Fighter: may not become Monk, Paladin or Sorcerer.
Monk: may not multi-class at all.
Paladin: may only become Fighter.
Ranger: may not become Monk, Paladin, Wizard or Sorcerer.
Rogue: may not become Monk, Paladin or Sorcerer.
Sorcerer: may not become Monk, Paladin, Fighter, Wizard, Cleric or Druid.
Wizard: may not become Monk, Paladin, Sorcerer, Ranger or Druid.

.) These rules are hardcoded in the level-up script, you can't cheat
it
.) Prestige Classes are not permitted on this server.

--- Cheating ---

.) Creating a second character to join the other army to harrass them or to gather information is one of the worst things you can do. This is TOTALLY OOC and will be punished harshly.
.) Transferring objects from one of your characters to another is totally OOC too and strictly forbidden. Only exception to the rule is if a DM allows to transfer items in rare circumstances (recreating a bugged character, correcting a character creation error).
.) Exploiting AI bugs is considered a cheat. Be it Creature Ping-Pong or any other exploit against the AI, it is strictly forbidden, and besides you're taking some fun from the game. This is your only warning. It is entirely possible that you will meet a slightly "buffed" monster if you abuse AI errors.
.) Running from AI to prevent further attack by using transitions is considered AI bug exploiting, and/or avoiding death, and is punishable by the rules stated above.
.) Transition Camping is NOT allowed. An example of this would be attacking someone as they load through a transition. To prevent this, be sure you and/or your party are far enough away they cannot see the blue transition square, and even then, a bit further away would be recommended. Punishment for this can range from a simple warning to a couple dragons and their families.

.) Every other cheat you can think of is forbidden. Unless otherwise stated, you will receive a warning for your first offense and the "new" cheat will be added to this list..
.) You may not play characters on either side of the war (Axfell/Cleaven) If you are caught breaking this rule we choose which character you may keep and delete the other off of the server's vault.
.) You may play characters of other factions that are not Cleaven or Axfell.
.) You may not "defect" from one party to join another and expect to be welcomed back if you change your mind...You may delete that character and start another one in the faction of your choice...but not change sides contiually. I.E. once you become a Shillar you may not go back to either Axfell or Cleaven factions.
.) Abusing roleplay xp is illegal and will result in loss of the xp you gained and more.

---Breaking Rules ---

.) Unless otherwise stated you will be given a warning for a first offense. If caught breaking the rules after that it is totally up to the DM that catches you what your punishment is. This may include anything from a loss of experience to a full ban from the server..
.) You may appeal the punishment via private msg on website (www.anphillia.com forums). List all facts and send screenshots for proof. We will review each case seperately and let you know of our decision.

--- DMs ---

.) It could happen that a DM tells you about a rule you don't find here. Rules are something that evolve over time, and certainly not all of them will be in here. DMs are the law, what they say counts and will probably make it into the rulebook at some point..
.) If you ask a DM about any matter and they say no DO NOT go to another DM and ask the same question with hopes they will say differently. Playing one DM against another is not tolerated. We are a team.

---Please have fun and enjoy your time here on Anphillia!

--- Appendix A - Examples --

--- Example XP Reward Calculations ---
.) Level 4
vs CR2: ~13
vs CR8: ~20
vs CR15: ~3
Drow/Duergar get 2/3 of that

--- Example XP Loss Calculations for Dying ---

.) Level 4
Death/Respawn: ~200 XP
Burning: ~130 XP

.) Level 8
Death/Respawn: ~1480 XP
Burning: ~370 XP

.) Level 12
Death/Respawn: ~3080 XP
Burning: ~770 XP

-- Appendix B - Changed Spells --

.) Isaac's Lesser Missile Storm
1d4+1 Damage / Missile
5 Missiles / Target maximum

.) Isaac's Greater MissileStorm
1d4+1 Damage / Missile
10 Missiles / Target maximum

.) True Seeing
Won't reveal good sneakers.

.) Flesh to Stone
Added mantle and SR checks
made invunerable to all kinds of damage and death magic

-- Appendix C - Known Bugs --

.) Sub-Race "Deep Gnome"
Is currently bugged at the moment- when you rest, the stats deep gnomes gain go away.</CExoString>
        </SubString>
    </CExoLocString>
    <CExoLocString Name="Description">
        <DWord Name="StringRef">4294967295</DWord>
    </CExoLocString>
    <Byte Name="Identified">1</Byte>
    <CExoLocString Name="LocalizedName">
        <DWord Name="StringRef">4294967295</DWord>
        <SubString>
            <Int Name="StringID">0</Int>
            <CExoString Name="String">Anphillia Rule Book</CExoString>
        </SubString>
    </CExoLocString>
    <Byte Name="ModelPart1">3</Byte>
    <Byte Name="PaletteID">54</Byte>
    <Byte Name="Plot">1</Byte>
    <List Name="PropertiesList">
        <Struct Id="0">
            <Byte Name="ChanceAppear">100</Byte>
            <Byte Name="CostTable">10</Byte>
            <Word Name="CostValue">5</Word>
            <Byte Name="Param1">255</Byte>
            <Byte Name="Param1Value">0</Byte>
            <Word Name="PropertyName">11</Word>
            <Word Name="Subtype">0</Word>
        </Struct>
    </List>
    <Word Name="StackSize">1</Word>
    <Byte Name="Stolen">0</Byte>
    <CExoString Name="Tag">AnphilliaRuleBook</CExoString>
    <ResRef Name="TemplateResRef">anphilliaruleboo</ResRef>
</Gff>
